(暗部)敵対する相手が上の場合
質的差を数量で埋めよ。
When facing a higher-skilled opponent...
make up for the difference
in quality with quantity!
あなたから教わった
基本戦術です。
That's the basic battle skills
you taught us.
(ダンゾウ)フッ…
年寄り１人に なんとまぁ…。
How can you do this
to an old man?
そこまで立ててくれるとはのぉ。
I can't believe you'd treat
someone this poorly...
綱手様の命により
あなたを捕縛し➡
On Lady Tsunade's orders,
you are to be captured and
brought back to the Leaf Village.
木ノ葉の里へ連行します。
(暗部)これは…。
(暗部)雨隠れの…。
What's this...?!
He's from the Hidden Rain...
Jet-Black Signal Fire
How To Make Friends
Dictionary of Social Relationships
How to Become Friends with Strangers
(ナルト)友達が
急に機嫌が悪くなったら…。
"If a friend suddenly gets
into a bad mood,
"the cause might be due
to changes in eating habits."
原因は 意外に
食生活の変化にあるのかも…。
うどんや そばの色と一緒で…。
"Like the color of soba
and udon noodles..."
フンッ… 何言ってるんだか
さっぱり わかんねえってばよ。
I have no idea what
they're talking about!
(サイ)実は ボクも…。
だよな だよな。
Well, neither do I...
Huh? What? Aren't there like
Cliff Notes or something
もっと簡単に
人の考えが わかるような➡
that explains human thought
in a simpler way?
虎の巻とか ねえのかなぁ。
サクラさんが そういうことは
経験で覚えろって。
Sakura said I should learn stuff
like this through experience.
Huh?! Heck no.
え!? イヤだってばよ…。
With him, it'll be a fierce struggle...
I mean...like a wild uproar.
あんな野郎と
くんずほぐれつ… じゃねえ➡
え～と ケンケンガク… ゴ… ガ… ゴ…。
Oh man... Anyway, we'd both go all out
and it'd be really ugly.
いや！ とにかく なんだ その…➡
ガチで つきあうなんてさ。
でも ナルトとソラなら➡
But I think understanding each other...
そういう
ぶつかって わかり合うのが➡
by butting heads would work
for you and Sora.
合ってるんじゃないのかな。
う～ん…。
ボクは やっぱ
そういうのが苦手だから➡
Well...I'm not really good with stuff like that...
もっともっと読まないと。
I have to read more about it.
ふ～ん… よくわかんねえ。
I don't really get it...
ソラのヤツ… ちっとは里に
慣れてきたと思ってたのにな。
That Sora...
And here I thought he was
getting used to things in the village...
What the heck happened to him?
いったい 何があったんだ…。
Lord Danzo...
《ダンゾウ様…》
(綱手)アスマとヤマトは？
Where are Asuma and Yamato?
(シズネ)呼んであります。
They have been summoned...
(綱手)説明しろ！ ダンゾウ。
Explain yourself, Danzo!
雨隠れとの国境が
不穏な この時期➡
Right now, when things are turbulent
at the border with the Hidden Rain,
why was it necessary to go
to the trouble of meeting
なぜ わざわざ危険を冒してまで➡
with a Shinobi from
the neighboring land?
隣国の忍と会う必要があった？
聞いているのか！
Are you listening?!
(ヤマト)待ってください…
この男 見覚えがある。
Wait a minute...
I've seen this man before...!
ボクが暗部にいた頃
任務中 行方不明になった➡
When I was with the Anbu,
he went missing during a mission.
確か 名は… タツジ。
As I recall, his name was...Tatsuji!
(アスマ)コイツ
ダンゾウ様が雨隠れに送り込んだ➡
So he was the spy Lord Danzo
sent to the Hidden Rain?
草だったのか。
(綱手)独断で いろいろと
嗅ぎ回っていたわけか。
So you were sniffing around
on your own, huh?
(綱手)雨隠れで
何を探っていたかは わからんが➡
I don't know what you were looking into
in the Hidden Rain...
つかんだ情報を聞かせてもらおう。
But you will tell me the information
you know.
Was the Hidden Rain involved
with the previous attack?
先の襲撃に
雨隠れは絡んでいるのか？
(ダンゾウ)クッ クッ クッ クッ…。
I can't believe you haven't
even figured that out yet...
その程度の情報すら
集まっていないとはな。
綱手姫…
穏健派を気取るのは結構だが➡
Princess Tsunade,
your conservativeness is fine with me...
But such complacency
will destroy this village!
その油断が里を滅ぼすぞ。
クッ… はなから語る気はないか…。
So you had no intention of talking
from the start, huh...?
いいだろう。 ならば…。
(ダンゾウ)やめておけ。
Very well. If that's the case...
Don't bother...
コヤツが
口を割るとでも思っているのか？
Do you think he'll talk?
フッ… やりようは いろいろあるさ。
There are many ways to do this...
(イビキ)お呼びですか？ 五代目。
You summoned me, Fifth Hokage?
頼んだぞ イビキ。
I'm counting on you, Ibiki.
Please leave it to me.
In just ten minutes I'll get him to talk.
お任せください。
10分もあれば
口を割らせてみせます。
(ホムラ)綱手… 何を あせっておる？
Tsunade... Why are you losing your patience?
火影たるもの
もっと どっしり構えておれ。
A Hokage is supposed to
act more dignified.
(ホムラ)
イビキまで引きずり出しおって➡
And you even dragged Ibiki into this.
駆け引きとしても いただけぬな。
This is unacceptable...
even as a strategy.
(コハル)よしよし… 苦労をかけたな。
Now, now...we'll handle this.
ダンゾウ…
タツジは お前だけの草ではない。
Danzo, Tatsuji wasn't just your spy.
He was sending us information
as well...
同時に
我々にも情報を流しておる。
(コハル)ホッ ホッ ホッ ホッ…。
同じ木ノ葉同士じゃ…➡
He's a fellow member of the Leaf...
He is not a double spy.
二重スパイとは言うまい。
(ホムラ)報告によると
今回の国境の襲撃に➡
According to the report,
the Hidden Rain was not involved
with the border attack.
雨隠れは かんでおらぬ。
More importantly, according to Tatsuji,
it seems he was assigned the other day
それより タツジの話では➡
先日 火ノ寺付近の隠し墓を
あばいたと思われる➡
on a mission to track and
monitor the group of four...
thought to be the ones who violated
the hidden tombs near the Temple of Fire.
４人組を追跡。
看視の任務にあたったそうだ。
それでは…。
お前たちが危惧したように➡
Then...
Just as you all feared,
it seems those four were trying
to get their hands on...
その４人は 火ノ寺の あの少年➡
that Sora boy from the Temple of Fire.
ソラを手に入れようと
しておったそうだ。
(ホムラ)綱手… お前も➡
Tsunade, you know about
the past incident that boy caused
過去に あの少年が
火ノ寺で起こした事件は➡
at the Temple of Fire, don't you?
知っておろう。
(綱手)あぁ。
(コハル)理由は わからんが➡
Yes.
I don't know the how,
but there is no doubt that boy
has some kind of power.
あの少年には 何らかの力が
あると見て間違いない。
Power equivalent to,
if not greater than,
ヤツらが奪った
守護忍十二士の亡骸と同等➡
that of the stolen Guardian
Shinobi Twelves' bodies...
もしくは それ以上のな…。
そのような
得体の知れない危険物を➡
I can't believe you'd invite something
so unknown and dangerous into the village.
里に招き入れるとはな…。
仮にも
この里を守護する里長ならば➡
If you're the leader of this village
dedicated to protecting it at all,
早急に決断するべきだろう。
you should make a decision immediately.
しかし このまま
火ノ寺に戻すわけにもいくまい。
But we can't just send him
back to the Temple of Fire.
ならば 幽閉か…。
Then should we incarcerate him?
いや… 里を脅かす災厄の芽は➡
No... The source of the disaster
threatening this village
根こそぎ摘まねばならん。
must be swiftly dealt with.
抹殺か…。
Extermination...?
((フリド : これが お前の本当の力だ))
This is your true power.
《ソラ : どうして
こう オレ様の力ってヤツは➡
Why is this power of mine
so ostracized?
うとまれる…。
This time... This time...
今度は… 今度は…。
アスマの おっさんよ…》
Old man Asuma...
綱手…
火影である お前が判断しろ。
Tsunade... You're the Hokage,
so you make the decision.
木ノ葉の益をよく考えてな。
Think hard about how
it will benefit the Hidden Leaf.
ことわ…。
(ソラ)離せ！
- I won't...
- Let go!
(ソラ)この野郎！
離せってんだ お面野郎!!
You jerk...!
Let go of me, you masked jerk!
(卯月)おとなしくしろ！
(綱手)ソラ！
Quiet down!
Sora!
(卯月)天井裏に隠れていました。
He was hiding in the back of the ceiling.
クソッ！
冗談じゃねえ！ なにが抹殺だ!!
Damn it!
Not a chance!
Extermination, my foot!
オレの力が
そんなに うっとおしいのかよ!?
Is my power that much of a nuisance?!
テメエらも
火ノ寺のヤツらと同じじゃねえか！
You jerks are the same as
the guys at the Temple of Fire!
お前は災いのタネだ。
ダンゾウ！
You're the seed of disaster.
Danzo!
クソッ！ どいつもこいつも！
何が仲間だ！ カカシ班だ！
Damn it! All of you jerks...
Comrades, my foot!
Forget Team Kakashi!
ソラ…。
Sora...
ちょっとでも
心を許しちまった このオレに➡
Are you saying I'm going to be punished
with divine retribution...
for trusting in people just the tiniest bit?!
罰が当たっちまった
っていうのかよ!?
静まれ ソラ！
アスマ！ アンタに聞きたいことがある。
Be quiet, Sora!
Asuma! I've got something
I want to ask you...
オレの…
オレの父さんを殺したのは…。
Did you...
kill my father?
((元守護忍十二士
裏切り者の… 猿飛 アスマだ))
The former member of
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve,
the backstabber Asuma Sarutobi.
父さんを殺したのは アンタか!?
Are you the one who killed...my father?!
オレだ。
Yes, it was me.
カズマにとどめを…
イヤ 殺したのは… オレだよ。
I'm the one who finished him...
I mean...killed him...
I was the one.
((カズマ : アスマ～！
カズマ～！))
Asuma!
Kazuma!
(ソラ)そういうことかよ…！
I get it now...
(ソラ)グォォ～！
これは…！
What's this...?!
よくも… よくも… よくも!!
How dare you! How dare you!
How dare you...!
(卯月)やめろ！
うぉ～!!
Stop!
Wha--?!
《この右手は…》
That...right hand...
《ソラ… お前の力は いったい…》
Sora...
What the heck is...your power...?
(ソラ)よくも… 父さんを！
How dare you...kill my father...
よくも…！
How dare you...!
うぉ～!!
うぉっ！
大丈夫か？ ソラ…。
You okay...Sora...?
ナルト…。
Naruto...!
テメエ
なに出しゃばってきやがった!?
You jerk! What're you doing sticking
your nose in this?!
ヘヘヘ… お前も言ってたじゃねえか。
You said it, didn't you?
((ソラ : 加勢に来たぞ。
I came to help.
誰も頼んでねえってばよ！
No one asked you.
(でも来ちまったものは
しようがねえ))
As long as I'm here,
I have no choice.
来ちまったものは
しようがねえだろ！
"As long as I'm here,
I have no choice," right?
テメエ！ なぜ ソラを襲う!?
You jerk! Why did you attack, Sora?!
根か…。
The Foundation, huh...?!
(ヤマト)ソラ！
Sora...!
ナルト…。
Naruto...?
大丈夫だってばよ。
I'm okay.
仲間を… オレの父さんを…
お前が裏切った！
You betrayed your comrades...
and my father...
父さんの敵！
I'll avenge my father!
ソラ！
待て！
Sora!
Wait!
あの バカ…。
That idiot...
うっ…。
ナルト！
Naruto...!
((忍僧 : コイツを絶対 外に出すな！
(忍僧)すべての門は閉鎖済みです。
Don't let him get outside
no matter what!
All of the gates have been closed.
よし！ では 破邪の陣で拘束する。
ハーッ！
All right, then restrain him
with the Destruction of Evil Seal!
ぐわぁ～!!
ぐはっ！
無念…
だが この先にある封印鉄壁は➡
This is mortifying...
But no one can destroy
the sealed iron walls up ahead...
何者にも破られは…。
(くっ…！))
What?!
また 同じ夢だってばよ…。
The same dream again...
玉が２つあるから
いけねえんだよ。
It's mistaken because there are two kings...
火ノ国の大名と 木ノ葉の火影…。
The Feudal Lord of the Land of Fire...
and the Hokage of the Hidden Leaf...
玉が２つあれば
必ずや混乱と疑心を招き➡
There will always be chaos
and distrust if there are two kings.
事あるとき判断は遅れ
他国の侵略を許すことになる。
And when anything happens,
decisions will be late and
the invasion of other lands will occur.
カズマの考えは いたってシンプルよ。
Kazuma's notion was very simple.
火ノ国よ １つにまとまろうぜ
ってことだからな。
He just wanted to unify
the Land of Fire as one...
が… カズマが正そうとしていた
２つの玉…➡
And...Kazuma attempted
to set the two kings right...
そのこと自体に
カズマは足元をすくわれた。
But he was tricked by
the very problem itself.
結局 この里の人間は
この里の玉につく。
At the end of the day,
the people of this village will stick
with this village's king.
アスマは 火影を
こっちの玉を選んだ。
Asuma chose the Hokage, this king...
(フリド)ヤツらは わかっちゃいねえ。
He doesn't understand
why this village can shine...
この里が輝ける その理由を。
本当の玉 火ノ国あってこそ
輝けるんじゃねえか。
The true king...
the Land of Fire's king allows it to shine!
(フリド)火ノ国のために…。
All for the Land of Fire...
That was Kazuma's cause.
それが カズマの義だ。
そのためにこそ➡
Isn't that why you were entrusted
with your power from Kazuma...?
お前の力は カズマから
託されたんじゃねえのか？
オレの義は 父さんの復讐だ。
それでもいい。
My cause...is revenge for my father.
That's fine. But look hard
at what's past that.
だが その向こうにあるもんを
見つめろ。
カズマが望む 真の復讐をだ。
At the true revenge Kazuma desires.
(フリド)ともに 行こう ソラ。
カズマの義を成し遂げるのだ。
Let's go together, Sora.
Carry out Kazuma's cause.
さすれば アスマを倒すチャンスなど➡
If you do that, I'll create as many chances
as you need to defeat Asuma.
いくらでも作ってやるよ。
(ソラ)もうひとつの玉…。
The other king...
火影…！
The Hokage...
(チョウジ)ソラ～？ ソラ～！
Sora!
(シカマル)まったく
めんどくせえ野郎だぜ…。
For crying out loud...
What a pain he is...
(キバ)チッ！
ニオイを追うのも ここまでか。
Is this as far as the scent goes...?
Hidden Leaf Hospital
(サクラ)ホント アンタの回復力ときたら
いつもながら感心するわ。
I'm always impressed by
your recuperative strength.
みんなで あちこち捜したのよ。
Everyone looked all over for him.
もう 里には いないのかも…。
He might not be in the village anymore.
いや… オレには まだ アイツが
里にいるような気がするんだ。
No! I get the feeling he's still in the village.
そうね。
Yeah...
(サクラ)それじゃ 今日は
ゆっくり やすんでなさい。
Okay, get some rest tonight.
あぁ。
Right...
《ソラのヤツ…》
That Sora...
このチャクラ…！
This Chakra...?
このチャクラの感じ…。 怒り？
This Chakra sensation...
Rage?
間違いねえ！
No doubt about it...
ソラ…！
Sora...!
ふぅ…。
綱手のばあちゃん！
Grandma Tsunade!
大丈夫か？ ばあちゃん！
あぁ。
You okay, old lady?!
Yeah...
ソラ！
Sora!
うお～っ！
《綱手 : なんだ!? このチャクラは！》
What's this Chakra...?
やめろ！
邪魔するな！
No!
Stay out of this!
お前 なんで ばあちゃんを!?
You! Why did you try to kill her...?!
Out of my way, Naruto!
どけ～！ ナルト！
綱手様！
Lady Tsunade!
クッ…。
待て！
ソラ！ ナルト！
Wait! Sora! Naruto!
待て！ ソラ！
Wait, Sora!
(シズネ)おや 珍しいものを
見てらっしゃいますね。
まっ たまにはな。
(シズネ)ナルト君から 三代目様まで➡
連綿と続く
師弟の流れってとこですか。
フフ… ん！
これは！
What? The power's out in the vil
(シズネ)あの ご意見番の お二人も➡
昔は ずいぶん
かわいかったんですね～。
どこが！ 全然かわいくないぞ！
(綱手)見ろ！ このナマイキそうな目
ふてぶてしい面構え！
まんま
面影が残ってるじゃないか。
ア アハハ…。
あっ！
なぁ そういや アイツの昔って➡
どんなんだろうな？
(シズネ)アイツ？
(綱手)ダンゾウだよ。
(シズネ)え～っ！
いや マズイですよ 綱手様！
な～に かまうもんか！
ちょ… 綱手様！
あった～！ これだ～！
よし いくぞ…。
ぬお～！
あひ～！
なんつ～か 思ったより アレだな…。